Hey, are you listening?!
I told you! The auto-locking
door was left wide open!
Don't make me repeat myself!
Operating Pro
1) Please
the room you wish to visit.
2) Please
confirm on the display.
3) Please
the room you're visiting.
I told you this last week, too!
Why am I paying such
high management fees?!
Huh?!
Screw you!
Do it today!
Come inspect it right now!
Are you even listening to me?!
I'll kill you!
JUJUTSU KAISEN
Kanada Taichi in Morioka, in June.
Name: Kanada Taichi\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
Gender: Male
Date of Birth: February 10th, 1984 (34 years old)
Blood-type: A
Height: 175cm / Weight: 63kg
History: Saitama Prefecture, Saitama Municipal Urami\h\h\h\h\h
Elementary School. Same city, Urami East Middle School. After\h\h
graduation, he enrolled in the same city's Iwasa Commercial\h\h\h\h\h\h
High School. Dropped out in second year. Hired by Misaki\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
Construction, INC. Worked as an on-site laborer for two years,\h\h
then changed jobs. Moved to Morioka City, Iwate Prefecture.\h\h\h\h\h\h
Worked for Sakino Civil Engineering, LTC for four years.\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
Transferred to Soma Manufacturing Inc. and worked as on-site
laborer. Currently still listed as an on-site supervisor at the\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
same company. He was confirmed dead inside the entrance of\h\h
his apartment in Morioka City on June 23rd of this year, just past \h
8:00 PM. It's believed he was stabbed to death by a cursed spirit.\h
Right before his death, a resident witnessed Kanada shouting on
the phone after returning from his shopping.
Name: Shimada Osamu\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
Gender: Male
Date of Birth: July 27th, 1983 (35 years old)\h\h\h\h\h\h
Blood-type: AB
Height: 169cm / Weight: 74kg
History: Saitama Prefecture, Saitama Municipal Urami\h\h\h\h\h
Elementary School. Same city, Urami East Middle School. After\h\h
graduation, he enrolled in Shounan Private High School and\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
graduated. He spent two years working several part-time jobs\h\h\h
doing construction work, office work, and independent\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
contracts. Afterward he enrolled in Tongmyong University, and\h\h
after graduating he joined Rinne & Kidd Inc. He worked there as
a programmer for four years before transferring to SRAD'D Inc.\h\h
He worked there as a system engineer until the present. He was\h
confirmed dead in front of the entrance of his apartment in\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
Tsurumi Ward, Yokohama, on August 18th of this year, around \h\h
3:00 PM. It is suspected that he was stabbed to death by a cursed
spirit when he returned home from a nearby convenience store.
Shimada Osamu in Yokohama, in August.
Name: Yamato Hiroshi\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
Gender: Male
Date of Birth: October 9th, 1983 (35 years old)\h\h\h
Blood-type: B
Height: 180cm / Weight: 69kg
History: Saitama Prefecture, Saitama Municipal Yoha\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
Elementary School. Same city, Urami East Middle School. After\h\h\h
graduation, he enrolled in the same city's Urami High School and\h
graduated. He then advanced to Kanbe Commercial College.\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
After graduating, he joined Bereact Inc. One year later, he\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
transferred to Sangent Inc. After working there for three years,\h\h\h
he transferred to Houwa Home Inc. There, he worked in sales for\h
the Nagoya branch until the present. He was confirmed dead inside
the entrance of his apartment in Midori Ward, Nagoya, on\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h
September 7th of this year, around 11:00 PM. It is believed that he\h
was stabbed to death by a cursed spirit upon returning from work.
Yamato Hiroshi in Nagoya, in September.
These three died in similar circumstances.
They were stabbed to death by a cursed spirit
at the entrances to their apartments,
and all of them had filed the same complaint
Jujutsu High Assistant Supervisor
Nitta Akari
m 0 0 l 0 -60 l 240 -60 l 240 0
with the property managers
several weeks before dying.
They claimed their auto-locking
doors were left wide open.
Episode 22: The Origin of Blind Obedience
None of the other residents have
any idea what could have happened.
None of the dates or locations match, though.
Could the same cursed
spirit have killed them all?
Hey, could the cursed spirit
be responsible for the doors?
Do sensors like those pick up cursed spirits?
They don't show up on
cameras and stuff, right?
Apparently, the cursed spirit made the
door operators go crazy, not the sensors.
Oh...
Operators?
And as for whether or not the same
cursed spirit was behind this...
Well, we couldn't be certain
from just the residuals.
After all, a lot of time had already passed.
So we tried to track down any
connections between the three.
We found that all three attended
the same middle school for two years.
Meaning all three received the same curse,
and it activated after time had passed?
Precisely. That's highly likely.
So we're going to that middle school now
to question someone
the three victims all knew,
and I want you three to see
what you can find as sorcerers.
Way to go, Kugisaki!
Heh. What'd you expect?
Spirit
Lantern
Morishita Family
Funeral 11:00~
A funeral?
Is this the home of that acquaintance?
Yes, it is...
Well, this sucks.
He died the same way the other three did.
Morishita
He lived with his family,
so there was no auto-locking door,
but he was killed in front of the entrance.
Previously, upon returning home alone,
he reported, "The door was unlocked,
but it wouldn't open,"
to his other family members.
Saitama Municipal
Urami East Middle School
Congratulations,
Making it to Koushien!
I asked his parents, too,
but they said they didn't know what
relationship he had with the other three.
Man, there goes our only lead!
Don't worry!
There has to be something
at this middle school!
I sure hope so.
For now, I've secured an appointment
with a teacher, so I'm counting on you.
Roger.
There's some obvious punks.
Let's beat 'em up and set 'em straight!
Why?
Huh?
I-It's good to see you!
Heh, look at that. You actually get it.
An aura just pours out,
even if you try to hide it.
We haven't seen you since
graduation, Fushiguro-san!
I... went here... for middle school.
Grinding
That's a surprise, too, but that's not the point!
Look at me!
What'd you do?!
What did you do in middle school?!
No, it would be quicker to ask them!
Hey, Idiot A and Idiot B!
What did this guy do to you?
We...
Or rather, every delinquent,
gang member, and so on in this area
got beaten up by Fushiguro-san.
I beat them up.
Why do you keep talking so stiffly?!
Grinding...
Look at me!
What are you doing?!
Hey! What are you doing?!
Hey!
Who are you? Students from other
schools aren't allowed in here!
And who the hell are you?!
He's clearly a staff member.
Why are you so combative?
We have permission to be here.
Oh, you're the ones?
You're all young.
You need to hang your pass around your neck.
Fushiguro-kun?
Hello.
He remembers you!
So this man's been here a long time?
Probably.
Takeda-san's a permanent employee.
Then I leave the rest to you!
Abandoning her duty...
Kanada, Shimada, Yamato...
and Morishita, huh?
I was shocked by their passing,
but I guess it's been nearly
twenty years since they graduated.
I remember it like it was yesterday.
They were problem children in their
own right, though not as bad as you.
What did you want to know?
Strange rumors, dark rumors,
connections to bad adults...
Hey, problem child!
...and anything of ill omen.
Dark rumors?
They may have been problem children,
but they never went beyond
average middle school stuff.
But wait... ill omen?
Do you mean that tale?
About the Yasohachi Bridge bungee jumping?
You're still here, A and B?
Yasohachi Bridge?
A notorious suicide spot.
It's well-known in this
area as a haunted location.
Oh, that's right! Back then, it was
all the rage among delinquents
to bungee jump off
Yasohachi Bridge late at night.
It was one of those tests of courage.
What a weird tribe.
I'm surprised there are people dumber than me!
What do you use for a cord?
We don't do it.
I just heard some students from our
parents' generation talking about it.
One day, Kanada and the other three
were absent without permission.
That wasn't all that unusual by itself,
but when we contacted their families,
we learned that those four hadn't
come home the day before.
It caused a pretty big stir.
Then they were found
unconscious under the bridge.
They got chewed out good,
but all four swore up and down
they didn't remember a thing.
I think that's it.
I've been to Yasohachi Bridge, too.
To bungee jump?
Ow!
It's easy for curses to take root in
haunted locations, just like in schools,
so people from Jujutsu High
regularly patrol it.
There wasn't anything unusual
at the time, though.
It might be a bit famous,
but it's still used as a normal bridge.
We still have to go check it out, though.
Yeah.
Fushiguro-kun?
Sorry, I was curious about something.
What is it?
Tsukimi-kun took awfully good care
of you when you were in school.
Is she doing well?
Yes.
Who's Tsumiki?
My older sister.
What?!
You tell us too little about yourself!
Yeah, that's right!
When they have cursed objects like these,
why don't they destroy them?
They can't destroy them.
Not when it comes to special-grades.
So they use a pact to put their life
on pause and prevent harm to others,
preserving their existence.
Sukuna's fingers cause harm, though.
That's an exception.
It's a monster that still
attracts curses over time,
even after becoming a cursed object
and divided into twenty pieces.
And because of that, it can choose its vessel.
Hmm... Then anyone works for these?
Hey, you.
Money?
Money, right?
I don't have that much!
But there are loan sharks and stuff, right?!
Will he work okay?
He still can't see me, even at this point.
He's seriously lacking in ability.
Here, say "ahh."
JUJUTSU KAISEN
We're here.
Koi no Kuchi Canyon, Yasohachi Bridge.
Koi no Kuchi Canyon, Yasohachi Bridge
Once you confirm a cursed
spirit's here, I'll lower a veil.
Roger!
Hey.
Sorry to ask this right after you woke up,
but could you go run a little errand for me?
Hey, we didn't find hide
nor hair of any cursed spirit.
Spicy Cod Roe
We didn't sense any presences or residuals.
Pounded Fish Cake is finally here!
I see.
Which means this isn't it.
Guess it's back to square one.
But isn't it bad if we take too long?
Why?
Well, it's a famous haunted location, right?
There might still be plenty
of others who got cursed.
And right now, the death rate's at 100%.
We don't want to see any others die, right?
True.
Ding-ding
Ding-ding!
Bungee jumping was all the rage then, right?
So maybe the act of jumping off is the key?
Did she say "ding-ding"?
Did she really say that?
She did! She did!
Itadori already tried that.
Huh?
What?! You mean you jumped
with that vinyl cord?!
Gyaaah!
Hey, there you are!
Thank goodness!
Fushiguro-san!
Who's that again?
Fushiguro's underclassman.
Remember how much you picked on him?
You were talking about Yasohachi Bridge, so...
I'm really glad I found you here!
Fujinuma?
A classmate.
My older sister.
I'm glad you remember me.
Bank ATM
I was talking to my sister
about you yesterday, and...
Um, Morishita-san had a
funeral in the neighborhood...
Then I heard from my brother that you were
looking into that man and Yasohachi Bridge,
so I started wondering
if they were related...
If what's related?
Morishita-san's death and the bridge...
They're not related.
We're just—
I...
I went there.
In eighth grade... I went to
Yasohachi Bridge at night.
Geh.
Has anything odd happened at home recently?
Any strange feelings that only
affect you and no one else?
My family runs a local branch shop...
Mugiwara
Open for business
and the shop's automatic door is
wide open only when I come home.
Mom and Dad both say it's just a coincidence,
but there's definitely something there.
It scared me.
That's when I heard about you,
and remembered the Yasohachi Bridge.
When did the issue with
your automatic door start?
It's happened about every other
day for exactly one week now.
There's at least two weeks between when the
four victims noticed something and their deaths.
We still have some time.
You didn't go to Yasohachi Bridge
by yourself at the time, did you?
Do you remember who you went with?
Um, so this really does
have something to do with...
Just with your automatic door.
But it has nothing to do
with Morishita-san's death.
Fushiguro-kun and the others are
helping me with my college report.
"Electromagnetic Waves from Haunted
Locations and their Effects on Electronics."
It's a huge pain in my gut!
But I want to hear from all kinds of people,
so I'd love to hear who you went with.
We'd better save her,
after lying to her like this.
I went on a test of courage
with two others from my club.
That's right. Fushiguro-kun,
Tsumiki-san was with us then, too.
Tsumiki?
That's Fushiguro's sister!
I see.
Then I'll try asking Tsumiki, too.
Okay, then I'll escort these two home.
Please keep working on the report.
Something's up, isn't it?
I can't let you both go home on one bike!
Fushiguro.
Fushiguro!
Fushiguro, snap out of it.
Make sure she's safe first!
I'm fine.
Sorry, I'm stepping away for a sec.
I understand the situation.
A guard for Tsumiki-san, right?
But the only ones we have available
right now are second-grade sorcerers.
Second-grade...
Since the number of victims
far exceeds our estimates,
we'll have to re-evaluate
the curse's grade, as well.
You were probably assigned to this mission
with Itadori-kun's growth taken into account,
so if it's even more dangerous than that,
it might be too much for
a second-grade sorcerer.
It's just as dangerous
for all of you, as well.
Personally, I recommend you withdraw.
What do I do?
Do I go back by myself right now?
No, the mission was already
dangerous for all three of us.
I can't leave it to just the two of them.
Gojo-sensei will return next week.
I could ask him then...
No, I can't! The time limit
is the big problem!
This isn't the type of cursed spirit
that attacks someone.
It's the type that activates a cursed
technique from within a marked person.
So there's no point staying
nearby and protecting them!
I have to exorcise it right away!
Why were you talking to Ijichi-san?
Is your sister Tsumiki okay?
She's fine.
More importantly, this mission's
danger level just shot up.
Other sorcerers will be taking over this case.
You two can go home now.
Huh? Why?
Us two? What about you?
I'll go back after I say farewell to Takeda-san.
Now go!
Thanks for your help.
Is this Nitta-san?
There's something I want to ask you.
The procedure, right?
Fujinuma-san didn't go
over Yasohachi Bridge.
They held their test of
courage under the bridge.
Itadori went under it, too.
Most likely, you can't get
below it from up above.
The cursed spirit is within its barrier,
so the procedure's important.
You go at night, from underneath.
And one more thing...
It's impossible to constantly keep a domain
imbued with a technique deployed forever.
Which means it's like that barrier
at the juvenile detention center...
an incomplete domain.
I'm actually lucky this time around,
since I won't need a veil.
You tell us too little about yourself.
Yeah.
You're seriously at your wits' end
if you didn't notice us until now.
We're not saying you have
to tell us everything,
but at least rely on us.
We're friends, aren't we?
Tsumiki's...
still bedridden.
The curse of Yasohachi Bridge
only appears before its victims.
Since she can't communicate herself,
I have no idea when she'll
be killed by the curse.
So I want to exorcise it right away.
But it's true that our mission's
danger level has increased.
Okay, okay, we get it now.
You should have told us that from the start.
The cursed spirit is within its barrier,
so the procedure's important.
You go at night, from underneath.
And one more thing...
At the bottom of the canyon,
there might be a river.
Crossing a river or other border—
acts that symbolize crossing to the afterlife—
carry important meaning in sorcery.
There it is.
This one will be rewarding to exorcise.
What's this? Someone beat me here?
Huh?!
Fushiguro, this one's
a different case, right?
Yeah.
Then you two focus on that other one.
I'll exorcise this one.
What?
You're going to play with me?
Juju Stroll
Help! It's a purse snatcher!
I run a Chinese restaurant.
Allow me to treat you as thanks.
We couldn't!
Are you sure?!
Thank you so much! I'll gladly eat!
Chinese Restaurant Manpuku
This restaurant has lasted four generations.
That was supposed to end with my father,
but I insisted and kept it running.
I wanted to keep this restaurant,
this flavor, around.
What a nice story.
Sorry for the wait. Here's our pride and joy,
the gyoza meal passed
down for generations!
Time to dig in!
Chinese Restaurant Manpuku
Thank you for the meal!
You two...
What do you think of gyoza
with no meat flavor,
that's basically just
cabbage and thickener?
I'm glad you said something, Fushiguro!
She was a nice woman, too!
She was a nice woman, but still!
But apparently, gyoza is meant to
be a vegetable dish, not a meat dish.
Seriously?
Episode 23:
The Origin of Blind Obedience - 2 -